James Anaipakos

Summary

- One year of experience in JavaScript development, fintech, and responsive design.
- Three years of experience as project leader, from two to six members.
- Active in the Open-Source community. Occassional public speaker.

Computer skills

Great JavaScript, HTML/CSS, Sass, React Concepts UI Design, MV* Frameworks, Agile Good Node, D3, Express, jQuery, Angular Databases SQL, MongoDB, Mongoose

Passable Meteor, Haskell, C, Python, IATEX Tools Git, Adobe CS, Grunt, Webpack, Gulp

Experience

2014-Present Capco, Associate Consultant, New York, NY.

- Remediated portion of international bank's \$1.45B regulatory fine by stepping into project manager role mid-project and steering the documentation enhancement of an Actimize anti-money laundering application's IT components.
- Revamped and successfully-deployed Sharepoint 2013 customer-facing website with **350+ combined pages** while working with seven developers and designers.
- Increased client understanding of anti-money laundering with D3, Express, and React application.
- Improved look and feel of Django dashboard while working with UX designer and Python developer.

2015–Present Manning Publications, Manuscript Reviewer, New York, NY.

• Improve six titles prior to publication by testing source code, verifying readability, and offering feedback on reader needs. Titles include CSS in Action, Learn Haskell, and Angular 2 in Action.

2015-Present Freelance Web Design, WordPress, New York, NY.

• Create and launch personal portfolio and sustainable goods WordPress sites for clients including Barrel On, Chicville USA, and With Purpose and Pepper.

2010–2012 **Department of Homeland Security**, Security Officer, Fort Lauderdale, FL.

• Exhibited critical thinking, subject matter expertise, and decision making by identifying security incidents, recognizing deviating behavioral patterns, and interviewing hundreds of passengers.

Projects

MEAN Dark Souls NYC, Dark Souls as Manhattan neighborhoods.

Angular 2 The Company We Keep, Manage stocks for the 2016 presidential candidates.

D3 + React Developer Salary Histogram, Average developer salary by state and year.

Node.js Ozymandias Chatroom, Start a private and shareable chatroom in seconds.

Highcharts QuantFlaunt, A satirical look at branding and data quantification.

jQuery Marxist Magic 8-Ball, Generate tweetable quotes from Jacobin magazine.

Education

2013–2015 Masters of Arts, Media Studies, 4.0 GPA.

Pratt Institute, Brooklyn, NY

2004–2009 Bachelors of Arts, Double Degree, English and Humanities, 3.5 GPA.

Florida State University, Tallahassee, FL